A Guide to the Marshall W. Fishwick Collection, c.1923-1935, 1940s-2006
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Marshall W. Fishwick Collection, c.1923-1935, 1940s-2006
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Fishwick, Marshall William, 1923-2006
Ms1985-007
97.3 Cubic Feet 70 boxes; 1 folder
This collection contains course and teaching related material, photos, manuscripts, audio and visual material, scrapbooks, and the professional and personal correspondence of Marshall William Fishwick, professor of Humanities and Communication Studies at Virginia Tech, 1976-2003.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisitions Information
The initial donation from the Marshall W. Fishwick Collection was received by Special Collections in 1985. The majority of the collection was donated in 2007.
Biographical Note
Marshall William Fishwick was born July 5, 1923, in Roanoke, Virginia. After receiving his BA from the University of Virginia in 1943, Fishwick served with the American Fleet during World War II. He then went on to receive his MA from the University of Wisconsin in 1946, followed by his PhD from Yale University in 1949.
In 1949, Fishwick began teaching at Washington and Lee University in Lexington, where he remained until 1962. He served as director of the Wemyss Foundation from 1962 to 1964, chaired Lincoln University's Art and American Studies departments from 1964 to 1970, and taught at Temple University from 1970 to 1976. From 1976 until his retirement in 2003, Fishwick taught at Virginia Tech, where he founded the American Studies and Popular Culture programs.
Fishwick co-founded the Popular Culture Association with Ray B. Browne and Russel B. Nye in 1970 and began the journal International Popular Culture. He wrote and contributed to more than 40 books, and received eight Fulbright Awards and multiple grants, which allowed him to teach abroad throughout Europe and Asia. He was a member of the Guild of Scholars of the Episcopal Church and historiographer of the Diocese of Southwest Virginia. One of Fishwick’s highest accomplishments as a multidisciplinary scholar was starting the academic movement in popular culture studies.
Fishwick married his third wife and Virginia Tech colleague Ann La Berge in 1995. He had four children with his first wife and two stepdaughters.
Marshall Fishwick died in Blacksburg, Virginia, on May 22, 2006.
Source:
Smith, Leanne E. "Marshall W. Fishwick (1923–2006)." In Encyclopedia Virginia. Accessed December 2, 2019. https://www.encyclopediavirginia.org/Fishwick_Marshall_W_1923-2006
Scope and Content
This collection contains course and teaching related materials, photographs, manuscripts, audiovisual and electronic material, scrapbooks, and the professional and personal correspondence of Marshall William Fishwick, professor of Humanities and Communication Studies at Virginia Tech, 1976-2003.
Arrangement
This collection is divided into three series based on material type:
Series I: Papers
Series II: Audiovisual and Electronic Materials
Series III: Oversize Materials
Arrangement (Papers)
The papers and photographic materials in this collection are in their original order. Folders were replaced and filed in new boxes in the order in which they were received, with the exception of books and a/v materials (see note below, as well as the "Separated Materials" note).
Arrangement (Audiovisual and Electronic Materials)
Note: Boxes 1-13 contain audiovisual and electronic materials from this collection, including VHS and cassette tapes, film, floppy disks, slides, and negatives. A spreadsheet of these materials by format is available for download and searching (file will automatically download).
Additional slides located in 2018 are not yet processed or listed in the spreadsheet. Contact Special Collections for more information.
Separated Materials (Books)
The following books were removed and cataloged for the Special Collections Rare Book Collection:
Brake, Robert J. Communication in Popular Culture. Bowling Green, OH: Bowling Green Popular Press, 1975. Copy 2.
Brown, Katharine L. Hills of the Lord: Background of the Episcopal Church in Southwestern Virginia, 1738-1938. Roanoke: Diocese of Southwestern Virginia, 1979.
Browne, Ray B. Against Academia. Bowling Green, OH: Bowling Green Popular Press, 1989. Copy 2.
Browne, Ray B., and Christopher D. Geist. Popular Abstracts. Copy 2.
Browne, Ray B., and Michael T. Marsden. Pioneers in Popular Culture Studies. Bowling Green, OH: Bowling Green Popular Press, 1999. Copy 2.
Cawelti, John G. The Six-Gun Mystique. Bowling Green, OH: Bowling Green Popular Press. Copy 2.
Eliot, T. S. Collected Poems, 1901-1935. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1936.
Fishwick, Marshall W. Around the World in Forty Years. Bowling Green, Ohio: Bowling Green State University Popular Press, c1984.
Fishwick, Marshall W. Common Culture and the Great Tradition: The Case for Renewal. Westport, Conn.: Greenwood Press, 1982.
Fishwick, Marshall W. The Face of Jang: A Collection of Poems. New York, Hobson Book Press, 1945.
Fishwick, Marshall W. Gentlemen of Virginia. New York: Dodd, Mead, 1961.
Fishwick, Marshall W. “If I were to Live All Over Again—”
Fishwick, Marshall W. Isle of Shoals. New York, N.Y., Hobson Book Press, 1946.
Fishwick, Marshall W. Lee After the War. New York, Dodd, Mead [1963].
Fishwick, Marshall W. Virginia: A New Look at the Old Dominion. New York, Harper [1959].
Fishwick, Marshall W. The Virginia Tradition. Washington, Public Affairs Press [1956].
Fishwick, Marshall W., ed. The World of Ronald McDonald.
LeBerge, Ann and Marshall Fishwick. From a Minimalist Kitchen: Simple Cooking for Post-Moderns.
Lippy, Charles H. Being Religious, American Style. Westport, CT: Greenwood Press, 1994.
Thompson, Jonathan R. Education and Literature in Virginia: An Address Delivered before the Literary Societies of Washington College, Lexington, Virginia, 18 June 1850. Richmond: H. K. Ellyson's Power Press, 1850.
Tompkins, Edmond Pendelton. Rockbridge County, Virginia: An Informal History. Ed. by Marshall W. Fishwick. Richmond, Whittet & Shepperson, 1952.
Van Auken, Sheldon. "The Southern Historical Novel in the Early Twentieth Century" in The Journal of Southern History, Vol. XIV, No. 2, May 1948.
Wolfe, Tom. The Bonfire of the Vanities. New York: Farrar, Straus, Giroux, 1989, c1987.
Separated Materials (Serials/Journals)
The following journals and serials were removed and cataloged for the Special Collections Rare Book Collection:
The Journal of Popular Culture.
The Journal of American Culture, vol. 27, no. 2; vol. 29, no. 1; vol. 29, no 2; vol. 29, no. 3.
The Journal of Popular Film, vol. 2, no. 1.
Popular Culture Association/American Culture Association conference programs, 1991-1993, 1997-1998.
The Southern Quarterly, Vol. XXI, No. 2.
Studies in Popular Culture, vol. 22, no. 3.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Faculty; Popular culture -- United States; University Archives; World War II
Organizations:
Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Series I: Papers
  - Transparencies and Handouts, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Class Notes and Handouts, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Transparencies, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Transparencies, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Plato (Cave)/Hamlet, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Explosion, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Popular Culture Intro. Syllabus, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Basic Definition & Culture Wheel, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Media Virus Book Review, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Southern Humanities Review, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Tech. Illusions of Progress, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Churchill Book Reviews, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Pamphlets, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Popular Arts and Culture Menu, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Fishwick Publications, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - American Studies: Hero, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Heros: O'Grady & Malcolm, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - American Studies Concentration, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - 1604 Exam, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Barbarians Data Entry Point, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Humanities Course List, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Sugar Bowl, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Fishwick Books, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - New York Times Popular Survey (2 Folders), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 24-25)
  - Comm 3037, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Comm 4034, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - New Globe: American Studies Concentration, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Popular Future Philosophy: "Umbrella", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - New Courses, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Fishwick Courses, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Utopia B.N.W. - Plato and Reality, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - "Nailed Down" Speech, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Freud/Darwin, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Springlore in Virginia, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - B2, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - C3, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - D4, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - E5, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - F6, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - G7, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - H8, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - I9, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - J10, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - K11, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - L12, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Mc 13, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - M14, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - N15, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - P17, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Q18, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - R19, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - S20, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - T21, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - V23, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - W24, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - X-Y-Z 25, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Fishwick Books, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Seeking New Synthesis, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - T.V. Intro., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Memoirs 2000+, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Arch. - Rodriguez, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - T.V., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Regionalism, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Popular Culture Topic Lectures, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Yellow Sulfur, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Hughes on F.L.W., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Griffiths, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Western/Stage Coach, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Popular Culture General Syllabus "Ready for Adventure", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Archetypes, Time, and Mosaic, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Christmas Parable = Chronicles, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Tasday, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Daily Notes & Outlines, Hughes Shock 4.0, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - International Popular Culture, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Black, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Aesthetics, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Transparencies and Class Notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Class Transparencies and Notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Class Notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Class Notes and Transparencies, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Transparencies, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Transparencies, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - Transparencies, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Transparencies, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - American Monroe and Madonna NBA Franchise, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Falling Star Check Up 1, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Barretts and Barnes, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bubberland, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Cathedral, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Cookbook, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Cox's Bazar, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Dale Avenue, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Drake, Fransis, 1914-2005 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Dreams/T.V./Freud, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Lady Eightball, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - New Eightball, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - New Eightball, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Evil, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Fishwick Books, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Folk to Pop, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Folklore, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Ford & ARF, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - France, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Gap, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Global Village, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Hero, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - In the Beginning - River, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Luddite, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Navy Novel, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - "Old Tom" Advanced Draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Oratory, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Pop = T.J., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - "Ray and Ronald Girdle the Globe", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Rome/Rain & Strolling, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - S.B. & the 5 Dreams, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Slade, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Song to Sing, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Springlore, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Style Wars, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Verbo, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Water, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - What's in a Name, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Wolfe, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Wolfe, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Fashion, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Wolfe, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Lee in Lexington, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Rockbridge Co., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Tash, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Fishwick Books, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Jordan, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Jordan Completed Essay, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Work in Prgress, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Hipps, Randy W., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Browder, Danya, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Publications, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Fall 2002, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Course Handouts, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Course Handouts, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Fishbk 3 Genlib, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Wick1 Genlib, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Fishwick Genlib, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Campus Quarterly, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Adalto, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Letters and Articles, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Fishbk 3 Genlib, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Fishbk 3 Genlib, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Rosen, Erick Notebook, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Writings and Photos, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Writings, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Fishbk 3 Genlib, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Fishbk 3 Genlib, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Aprinum, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Garnett, Mathew, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - DeKerna, Margarite A., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Around the World in 40 Years, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Popular Culture Course Handouts, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Unpublished Book ? - No Title, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - What's Next for the Left, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - External Dream, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Photos, Writings, and Articles, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Tradition, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - South Intro - Remus/Henry, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Scenario for Sardines, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Block Pop, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Icons/Idols, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Toyn Bee/McLuhan, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Mac-Spoiled, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Devil, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Folklore, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Americana: Popular Culture in the Round, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - History: Study of Fact, System, Etc., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Contessa, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Caesar, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Philosophy/Rain, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Cicero, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Big Mac, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - To Add, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Culture, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - George Washington, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - George Washington Since '76, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Larry Grimes, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Spring Lore, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Craig Heating, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - 17 R. Rustic, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - 18 Survival Tactics, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Prints TV Use, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Bath Berkley, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Conclusion, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Bibliography and Notes, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Rockbridge, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Extra Prints and Duplicates, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Sweet Sulphur Continued, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - C. Worsham, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - 19th Century Photo Album, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Letters From 1800s, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Preston Letters, 1700-1899 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Prints - Lexington, VA, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Greatness on Glass, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - R. Mudd, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - VMI Photos, 1871-1877 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 9, Folder 1)
  - Letters and Photos from Washington and Lee & Virginia Historical Society, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Church and Cicero, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Articles and Editorials, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Writings - Jordan, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - All the King's Horses - Musical, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Alone Mill, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Natural - B., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Lady, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Popular Culture, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Sam Houston, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Chronology Plot, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - House (5 Universe), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Working New, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Fast Pace, Fast Food, MTV, Big Mac, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Hero In Transition, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - 4034, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - TJ High School, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Unembarrassed Muse, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Books versus Elec. Age (Review), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Salzburg Seminar, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Spring Calender, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Topics, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Class Notebook Guide, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Working Journal, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Humanities 1604 Intro, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Religious Awakening, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Custom Publishing, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Anti-Hero: Cowboy, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Elvis, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - What is Art, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Kinko's, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - 1604 Syllabus, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Humanities 1604-2946, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Popular Religion, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Fishwick Books, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Ideas, Objects, Things, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Humanities/Arts Introduction, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Humanities 2504, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Humanities 3024, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - "Awakenings" Complete MSS, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Faulkner (TTT) Lee at Washington and Lee, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - I.P.C. - Powers, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Class Notes, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Class Notes, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Hero: Campbell, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Family Photos, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Family Photos, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Fishwick and Christmas Pictures, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Mosaic Pictures, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Pictures, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Pictures to Use, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Pictures & "Weirdo" Drawings, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Photos, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - PPubs & Pictures, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Book Pictures, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Pictures - Use!, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - MWF Various, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Family Photos/Memos, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - UVA, 1940-1942 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - UVA, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - 1890s, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - JP's #80, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Personal, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Navy, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Autobiography, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Europe, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Europe, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - 80!, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - [U.S.S.] ATR - (8), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - United States Navy, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - New MF, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Fishwick's Clan, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - College Work, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Dream Book, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Retirement Certificate, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - The Mink - Washington and Lee, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Fishwick Personal and Work Documents, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Fishwick Personal and Work Documents, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Personal and School Documents, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Photos, Etc., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Photos, Etc., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Poland, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Photos & Church Related Items, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Historic Photos, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Historic Photos, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Memoirs and Resigned, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Memoirs, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Memoirs, etc., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - In Defense of P.C. / Apologetic Confessions & Ex-Elitist, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Books & Academic Notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Retirement, Photos, Writings, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Extra Wills and Death/Obituary, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Nomination for Alumni Distinguished Professor, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Alleg = Crockett, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Blue, Craig, Virginia Mineral, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - C.W. 1,2,3, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Crow / Cabell, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Hot = Homestead, Warm and Healing, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Montgomery White, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Rockbridge, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Spring T.V., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Sweet Calby, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Yellow Sulphur, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Writings, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Fake-lore / FAD, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - GAP, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Empire, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Religion, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Black, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Popular Mythology, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Poetry Book, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Cookbook, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Disting, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Writings, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Writings, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - R.T. - M.F., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Pleasants Joannet, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - MWF Evaluations, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - France, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Copy, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Walden & MWF, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Autobiography Confessions, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Autobiography, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Autobiography, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Autobiography, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Personal Documents, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Package to "Family Pleasants", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - 1940's Personal Correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Jokes, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Photos, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Photos, Etc., n.d. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, News Clippings, Etc., n.d. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Travel, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Southern Tradition and Contemporary Architecture, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Lifestyles, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Hunter's Raid, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Denmark, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Children, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Novel, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 11)